Joel Olawanle

Technical writer and Frontend Developer, highly skilled at translating designs to frontend codes.

17, Olaseun Street
Ondo City, Nigeria
(234) 70-3552-2621
olawanletjoel@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am a Software engineer who loves teaching and growing communities. This has made me write over 130 technical articles published on several platforms for developers all over the world to access and learn.

As a Technical writer I have worked with so many experts who have always been amazed by my writing. I write articles that are very clear and easy to understand with my target audience in mind.

EXPERIENCE

CoderPad - Guest Technical Writer

AUGUST 2022 - PRESENT

I write frontend technical articles for CoderPad blog.

Freecodecamp - Staff Writer

JUNE 2022 - PRESENT

I write technical articles for FCC English publication as a means of helping the developers community and giving back to the community because I learned how to code via the FCC platform. Here is my profile.

Hygraph - Guest Technical Writer

FEBUARY 2022 - PRESENT

I write technical articles for Hygraph blog.

CSS Tricks - Freelance Technical Author

MAY 2021 - PRESENT

I write frontend-related technical articles on <u>css-tricks</u>.

ContentLab.io — Contract Technical Writer

MAY 2021 - PRESENT

I write technical content for various organizations that looks up to contentlab for their content.

Stack Abuse - Freelance Technical Author

FEBRUARY 2022 - JULY 2022

I write frontend-related technical articles on stack abuse.

Logrocket— Freelance Technical Writer

AUGUST 2020 - JANUARY 2022

I write frontend-related technical articles on logrocket.

SKILLS

Programming - HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Sass, React, Vue, TailwindCSS

JamStacks - Nuxt, Next & Gridsome.

Version Control - Git

Design - Photoshop, CorelDRAW, AdobeXD, Figma

Others - WordPress

SOFT SKILLS

- Teamwork and Team Building.
- Effective Communication.
- Critical thinking, Creativity, and Problem-solving.
- Open-mindedness and Adaptability.

AWARDS

NACOSS OSUSTECH Computer Science Best Instructor (frontend) of the year (2021).

LANGUAGES

English Language

Sanity.io - Technical Author (Contract)

APRIL 2021 - NOVEMBER 2021

I write frontend-related technical articles on sanitv.io.

Draft.dev— Contract Technical Writer

AUGUST 2021 - DECEMBER 2021

I wrote 4 technical content for various organizations which look up to Draft for content.

Spacepen Technologies, Lagos—Intern

MAY 2020 - JULY 2020

I worked and learned much as a remote Intern with spacepen.

PROFILE LINKS

Writing Profiles

LinkedIn

Github

Twitter

Portfolio

EDUCATION

Ondo State University of Science & Technology, Okitipupa, Nigeria — *Degree*

JANUARY 2018 - PRESENT

Currently pursuing a degree in Computer Science to attain a B-Tech certificate.

PROJECTS

<u>OPQ</u>— An App built with Nuxt.js and Tailwind CSS that helps students access all past questions for free instead of consulting their seniors.

I suggested this idea to my colleagues, and we decided to build this app. I have worked on many other projects while learning, which are all on Github.

<u>DV App</u> (Drug verification App) — An App built with Nuxt.js and PHP helps people verify their drugs before using them.

I worked with a team of people as part of a build4sdg developers challenge and came up with the idea to verify drugs before using them. We used PHP to work on the backend and develop an API, which I used for the frontend.

<u>Covid Hack</u> — An App built with JavaScript and Framework7.

I worked with a team of people as part of a twillo and Dev community hackathon by developing an app to get updates about COVID-19 even when offline. We were runner-up in this competition. <u>Here</u> is a link to our detailed article.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Inventors Community — Frontend *Lead*

I have always been a member of the inventors' community in OAUSTECH where I learned programming skills as a student. My commitment to the community and growth generally earned me the position of a core team member for about two years, actively planning workshops and training others students. In 2021, I was made the frontend lead to help train students and make them better frontend developers.

Open-Source Community Africa (OSCA)— LEAD

I just got accepted as a lead for a newly formed Open-Source community in Okitipupa. I will be introducing many people to the world of Open Source.

Google Developers Student Club (GDSC OSUSTECH)— CORE TEAM MEMBER

I have been a Core Team member for over 1 year now, assisting the Lead to build the Tech community in my school. I also helped by creating visual designs for workshops, events, seminars, e.t.c

Wikipedia— OPEN-SOURCE CONTRIBUTOR

I improved the documentation by fixing some Typos, bugs, and cleared an issue that has lasted for over a month. I made about 4 Pull Requests to the Wikimedia UI Style Guide repository on GitHub, of which all got merged.